Daniel Cox

Dartmouth, NS, Canada Phone: (902) 818 – 8129

Email: danielcox996@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/daniel-cox-b0320115b Website: https://dangerousdaniel.github.io/

PROFILE

I am a grad from Nova Scotia Community College IT Programming class 2020. I love creating games of my fantasy stories of saving the world from evil. I enjoy helping with a computer on how to use for the everyday task (basic to advance.) I am excellent at creating Web Applications for projects, and I have led a few teams through the start of the program, leading them to a good point to continue their products into a successful project.

Throughout my experience as a student and a Unity developer, I completed computer programming projects at NSCC. These projects taught me a hands-on mindset and approach. I learned how to analyze, study, and apply learning to figure out solutions when working alone or with a team.

I'm currently creating a 2D fantasy platform game named Vex Monsters, where you save monsters from evil betrayed. It is in the development stage, and I'm the Team Leader, where I create the story and programming the game mechanics and User interface for the game.

Vex Monsters is my passion project, where I can bring people together to bond over fun RPG, platform gaming. My vision is to expand this project and build to build console gaming community here in Halifax.

EDUCATION

IT: Programming September 2018 – May 2020

NSCC IT Campus, Halifax, NS

September 2017 – May 2018 Academic & Career Connections

NSCC IT Campus, Halifax, NS

• Completed Math 12 and English 12.

Adult Learning Program September 2016 – June 2017

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

• Skills development in math.

High School Diploma September 2014 – June 2015

Prince Andrew High School, Dartmouth, NS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dishwasher/Prep Cook

June 2021 - Present

Finbar's Portland Hills, Dartmouth, NS

- Working quickly to clean dishes and cooking equipment.
- Preparing food and ingredients to be used during service.
- Resupplying the kitchen when needed.
- Follow best safety practices and maintain a clean and safe work environment.

Senior Developer

November 2019 – March 2020

Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax, NS

- Lead team of 7 junior developers in handling various development tasks in support of IT Job Fair
- Front-end and back-end development in Laravel Framework
- Maintaining a Project Board on Trello and Github
- Website: itjobfair.ca/

Line Cook

November 2018 - June 2021

Dairy Queen, Dartmouth, NS

- Successfully completed food safety training
- Prepare setup and food for the day
- Use various cooking methods and equipment to specified recipes and standards
- Follow best safety practices and maintain a clean and safe work environment
- Work independently and in a team environment

Junior Developer

April 2019 – May 2019

Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax, NS

As a junior developer, I assisted in developing an online trading card game. My role focused on developing the home page, Player's page, as well as incorporating responsive design into the site. This involved using HTML and CSS to create the website. The team used GitHub to assign tasks.

Dishwasher

July 2016 – November 2018

Swiss Chalet, Dartmouth, NS

- Keep up a fast pace during rush hours to ensure adequate dishes were clean.
- Provide my employer with a flexible schedule, which allowed me to go in to work on short notice.
- Maintain a neat and tidy workplace to ensure health and safety standards were met.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Team Coordinator

September 2019 - March 2020

NSCC IT Job Fair & Conference- 2020, Dartmouth, NS

Responsible for helping managed the team by tracking team minutes, participating in meetings, being a part of the leadership group and helping track loose ends.

IT Technician May 2017 - Present

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

- Diagnose computer problems, monitor computer processing systems, install software and perform tests on computer equipment and programs.
- Set up computer equipment, schedule maintenance and teach clients to use programs.
- Perform computer repairs and computer parts ordering.
- Maintain an inventory of over 40 computers.

Sales Clerk

September 2015 – June 2016

Common Values and Mort's Convenience, Dartmouth, NS

- Processed purchases and kept accurate records of daily sales.
- Conducted monthly product inventory to allow sufficient stock to be ordered for the next month.
- Ensured a tidy and safe work environment by completing a daily cleaning list.

MAMBEC Senior Instructor

March 2014 - June 2015

Martial Art Mind-Body Education Centre (MAMBEC), Dartmouth, NS

- Trained children in Martial Arts and self-discipline.
- Worked year-round on weekends, school professional development days and summer vacation.
- Completed over 500 Leadership/Volunteer hours.

PROJECTS

Vex Monsters December 2019 – Present

- Vex Monsters is a 2D fantasy platform game, where you save monsters from the evil betrayer.
- Team Leader
- Programming the logic and User Interface of the game from moving the player, ai, dialogue, NPC, and other game mechanics.
- Story Writer for the backstory
- Maintaining a Project Board on Trello
- Conduct weekly Scrums

ADDITIONAL TRAINING & ACHIEVEMENTS

| Challenge NS 2017 Second Place | 2017 |
|--------------------------------|------|
| Occupational Health & Safety | 2017 |
| WHMIS | 2017 |
| MAMBEC Martial Art Black Bel | 2012 |